<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World News &#8211; JCM Judiciary</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/world-news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 16:24:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/live-favicon.jpg</url>
	<title>World News &#8211; JCM Judiciary</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>UN Rights Chief Urges Probe Over Israel&#8217;s Gaza Bombardment</title>
		<link>/un-rights-chief-urges-probe-over-israels-gaza-bombardment/</link>
					<comments>/un-rights-chief-urges-probe-over-israels-gaza-bombardment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Rights Chief Urges Probe Over Israel's Gaza Bombardment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN human rights chief on Friday urged an investigation into what he called Israel&#8217;s use of &#8220;high-impact explosive weapons&#8221; in Gaza, which he said was causing indiscriminate destruction in the besieged Palestinian enclave. Volker Turk, the UN High Commissioner...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The UN human rights chief on Friday urged an investigation into what he called Israel&#8217;s use of &#8220;high-impact explosive weapons&#8221; in Gaza, which he said was causing indiscriminate destruction in the besieged Palestinian enclave. Volker Turk, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, said Israel must end its use of such weapons in the densely populated area, home to 2.3 million Palestinians, half of whom have been displaced by fighting in the last month. Turk was not specific about what weapons he was referring to. Asked for comment, the Israeli military said it was making checks and would respond later.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Israel&#8217;s air, sea and land bombardment of Gaza, accompanied now by a ground assault deep inside the territory, aims to destroy the militant group Hamas which controls Gaza. Hamas killed 1,400 Israelis in a cross-border Oct. 7 attack, according to Israeli tallies, and the U.N. has said the assault involved war crimes. Israel&#8217;s subsequent bombardment of Gaza has killed more than 10,000 Palestinians according to health authorities in the Palestinian enclave. The extensive Israeli bombardment of Gaza, including the use of high-impact explosive weapons in densely populated areas is clearly having a devastating humanitarian and human rights impact, Turk told a news conference during a visit to Jordan&#8217;s capital Amman.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The attacks must be investigated, We have very serious concerns that these amount to disproportionate attacks in breach of international humanitarian law. Israel blames Hamas for civilian deaths in Gaza, saying the group uses the population as human shields and hides weapons and equipment around hospitals, which have been hit by bombardments. Any use by Palestinian armed groups of civilians and civilian objects to shield themselves from attack is in contravention of the laws of war, Turk said. &#8220;But such conduct by Palestinian armed groups does not absolve Israel of its obligation to ensure that civilians are spared. Turk also said Israel must take immediate measures to protect Palestinians in the occupied West Bank, where violence is escalating between Palestinians and Israeli soldiers and settlers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Turk said at least 176 Palestinians, including 43 children and one woman, had been killed in incidents involving Israeli security forces since the beginning of October. At least eight Palestinians had been killed by Israeli settlers. Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas and said it has also been conducting counter-terrorism operations against militants from the group and other Palestinian armed factions in the West Bank. Over the past 18 months, Israeli troops have killed hundreds of Palestinians &#8211; hardened militant fighters, stone-throwing youths and uninvolved civilians &#8211; and made thousands of arrests across the West Bank. In the same period, dozens of Israelis have been killed in attacks by Palestinians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/un-rights-chief-urges-probe-over-israels-gaza-bombardment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Drone’s View Behind Russian Lines Cratered Fields and Charred Armor</title>
		<link>/a-drones-view-behind-russian-lines-cratered-fields-and-charred-armor/</link>
					<comments>/a-drones-view-behind-russian-lines-cratered-fields-and-charred-armor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 15:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cratered Fields and Charred Armor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The images a reconnaissance drone sent back to Ukrainian forces provided a vivid portrait of the Russian side of the war zone. Damaged houses gave way to cratered fields on Ukraine’s southern steppe. There was burned-out armor in a scorched...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The images a reconnaissance drone sent back to Ukrainian forces provided a vivid portrait of the Russian side of the war zone. Damaged houses gave way to cratered fields on Ukraine’s southern steppe. There was burned-out armor in a scorched forest. A jagged Russian trench along a tree line had been blasted by American-supplied cluster munitions barely a week earlier, according to Lt. Ashot Arutiunian, the commander of the unit that recorded the images.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He pointed to holes in the roofs of several large agricultural buildings in a village and said they had most likely been hit by the American-made HIMARS rocket system; it is known for its accuracy, and there was no damage to surrounding buildings or to a nearby church. This was on a recent morning, with Ukrainian artillery firing relentlessly, the deep rumbling explosions of the impact resonating in the distance. Mixed in were the louder explosions of Russian shells landing on Ukrainian positions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">But Lieutenant Arutiunian was focused on the skies above. Drones have become a mainstay used by both Russian and Ukrainian forces, reconnoitering the battlefield and directing fire against enemy targets. Lieutenant Arutiunian, who uses the military call sign Doc — a reference to the doctorate in data mining he holds from Kyiv Polytechnic — commands four teams in the unmanned aerial vehicle service of the Ukrainian Volunteer Army, operating on the southern front. They deploy a variety of propeller-driven drones and planes to track Russian forces for the Ukrainian military and are constantly adjusting tactics and equipment to evade Russian interceptors.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This week, one of the units allowed a team of New York Times journalists to accompany it on a mission close to the front line as it sent a drone into Russian-occupied territory to surveil the battlefront. A condition was that the unit’s precise location could not be reported. Amid a background of artillery fire, the team got to work under cover of a small copse of trees, unpacking equipment and setting up four antennas; those were needed to work round the threats of both Russian and Ukrainian electronic jammers that can swiftly end the flight of a drone.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The fixed wing craft the unit’s members were using was equipped with two cameras and an independent global positioning system as backup, to give the pilot several options to bring it home should one or more of the systems fail. In this reconnaissance mission we are investigating the terrain, Lieutenant Arutiunian said. Later, back at base, they would examine the video footage on a big monitor to try to spot Russian military, he said: “We are looking for soldiers, warehouses, gasoline depots, whatever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-drones-view-behind-russian-lines-cratered-fields-and-charred-armor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>20 Killed in Cameroon Separatist Attack</title>
		<link>/20-killed-in-cameroon-separatist-attack/</link>
					<comments>/20-killed-in-cameroon-separatist-attack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 22:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[20 Killed in Cameroon Separatist Attack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Separatist rebels yesterday killed around 20 people, including women and children, in an attack on a village in one of Cameroon&#8217;s restive anglophone regions, the government said. The overnight assault occurred at Egbekaw village, western Cameroon, the scene of deadly...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Separatist rebels yesterday killed around 20 people, including women and children, in an attack on a village in one of Cameroon&#8217;s restive anglophone regions, the government said. The overnight assault occurred at Egbekaw village, western Cameroon, the scene of deadly clashes between rebels and government forces for seven years. There were men, women and children, more than 20 killed,&#8221; minister at the presidency Mengot Victor Arrey-Nkongho told public radio. It&#8217;s intolerable.&#8221; Cameroon&#8217;s primarily English-speaking Northwest and Southwest regions have been gripped by conflict since separatists declared independence in 2017. That followed decades of grievances over perceived discrimination by the francophone majority.</p>
<p>Donald Trump was in a New York court yesterday to testify in a civil fraud case threatening to cripple his real estate empire, the first former president to take the stand as a defendant in more than a century. The 77-year-old Republican arrived shortly before 10:00 am (1500 GMT) to testify in the Manhattan courtroom before Judge Arthur Engoron. Trump, the frontrunner for the 2024 Republican presidential nomination, denounced the case as &#8220;very unfair&#8221; as he arrived for his testimony, calling it political lawfare&#8221; and &#8220;election interference. It&#8217;s a very sad situation for our country, he said. &#8220;It usually takes place in third world countries.</p>
<p>Trump and his two eldest sons, Don Jr and Eric, and other Trump Organization executives are accused of exaggerating the value of its real estate assets by billions of dollars to obtain more favorable bank loans and insurance terms. New York Attorney General Letitia James, speaking to reporters before Trump&#8217;s arrival, said the real estate tycoon &#8220;consistently misrepresented and inflated the value of his assets.&#8221;Before he takes the stand, I am certain that he will engage in name-calling and taunts and race-baiting and call this a witch hunt,&#8221; James said. &#8220;But at the end of the day, the only thing that matters are the facts and the numbers.</p>
<p>And numbers, my friends, don&#8217;t lie. Trump has repeatedly attacked James, who is Black, and the judge overseeing the case calling him &#8220;unhinged&#8221; and a &#8220;Trump-hating radical left, Democrat operative. Engoron has responded by slapping Trump with two fines &#8212; one for USD 5,000, another for USD 10,000 &#8212; when he ruled the onetime reality television star had violated a partial gag order imposed after he bashed the judge&#8217;s clerk on social media. Trump&#8217;s testimony follows that of his sons Don Jr and Eric, who took the stand last week and blamed accountants for the financial statements of the company.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/20-killed-in-cameroon-separatist-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iraq Dig Unearths 2,700-year-old Winged Sculpture</title>
		<link>/iraq-dig-unearths-2700-year-old-winged-sculpture/</link>
					<comments>/iraq-dig-unearths-2700-year-old-winged-sculpture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 19:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[700-year-old Winged Sculpture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq Dig Unearths 2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A dig in northern Iraq has unearthed a 2,700-year-old alabaster sculpture of the winged Assyrian deity Lamassu, which was found largely intact despite its large dimensions. Only the head was missing and that was already in the collection of the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A dig in northern Iraq has unearthed a 2,700-year-old alabaster sculpture of the winged Assyrian deity Lamassu, which was found largely intact despite its large dimensions. Only the head was missing and that was already in the collection of the Iraq Museum in Baghdad after being confiscated by customs officers from smugglers in the 1990s, the dig&#8217;s French leader Pascal Butterlin said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I never unearthed anything this big in my life before, Butterlin said of the 18-tonne sculpture measuring 3.8 by 3.9 metres (about 12.5 by 12.8 feet). Normally, it&#8217;s only in Egypt or Cambodia that you find pieces this big. The attention to detail is unbelievable, said the professor of Middle East archaeology at the University of Paris I Pantheon-Sorbonne.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Erected at the entrance to the ancient city of Khorsabad, some 15 kilometres (10 miles) north of the modern city of Mosul, the sculpture shows the Lamassu, an Assyrian deity with a human head, the body of a bull and the wings of a bird. It was commissioned during the reign of King Sargon II who ruled from 722 to 705 BC and erected at the city&#8217;s gates to provide protection, Butterlin said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">First mentioned in the 19th century by French archaeologist Victor Place, the relief dropped from public records until the 1990s when Iraqi authorities earmarked it for &#8220;urgent intervention&#8221;. It was during this period that looters pillaged the head and chopped it into pieces to smuggle abroad. The rest of the relief was spared the destruction wreaked by the Islamic State jihadist group, which overran the area in 2014, because residents of the modern village of Khorsabad hid it before fleeing to government-held territory, Butterlin said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/iraq-dig-unearths-2700-year-old-winged-sculpture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
